<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>za.co.antsprojectshub.OneUp</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>OneUp</name>
  <summary>Update openSUSE packages, Flatpaks and firmware from one window</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      OneUp is a one-click update dashboard for openSUSE (Tumbleweed and Leap). It
      wraps the correct command-line update steps behind a simple panel, so you do
      not have to remember them or juggle several tools:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>System packages — zypper dup --allow-vendor-change on Tumbleweed, zypper update on Leap</li>
      <li>Flatpak apps — user and system scope, with unused runtimes pruned</li>
      <li>Device firmware — via fwupd</li>
      <li>Housekeeping — a safe clean-up of leftover dependency packages and the download cache</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Each step is a toggle, so you choose what runs. OneUp itself never runs as
      root — it asks for your password once through the desktop's standard prompt
      and streams a live log of everything it does.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">za.co.antsprojectshub.OneUp.desktop</launchable>
  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
    <category>PackageManager</category>
  </categories>
  <keywords>
    <keyword>update</keyword>
    <keyword>zypper</keyword>
    <keyword>flatpak</keyword>
    <keyword>firmware</keyword>
    <keyword>openSUSE</keyword>
  </keywords>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/milnet01/OneUp</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/milnet01/OneUp/issues</url>
  <developer id="za.co.antsprojectshub">
    <name>Anthony Schemel</name>
  </developer>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The OneUp panel with all update tasks toggled on</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/milnet01/OneUp/main/screenshots/oneup.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>Release 1.1.0.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Each repository in the Repositories manager now shows a plain-English line describing what it's for.</li>
          <li>A Repositories manager (from the header) to turn software repositories on/off with switches and remove ones that duplicate another repo's URL — the duplicate-repo warning now opens it.</li>
          <li>Each task row now shows how long the step took next to what it did — e.g. "3 installed · 42s".</li>
          <li>An "About" window (from the header) showing the version, MIT licence, GitHub and openSUSE package links, and a manual "check for updates" button that reports the result either way.</li>
          <li>A desktop notification when an update you started finishes — so a run you walked away from still tells you it's done (only pops up when the window isn't focused).</li>
          <li>The current version is shown in the window title and header.</li>
          <li>Flatpak reports how many apps it updated (counted before the update, like the check does).</li>
          <li>Each task row now shows what happened after a real update — e.g. "3 installed", "Up to date", "Updated", "Failed" — not just after a check.</li>
          <li>The Repositories manager is wider so repo URLs aren't clipped and remembers its size; the About and Repositories popups now open centered over the main window.</li>
          <li>The duplicate-repository warning now names the offending URL and tells you how to remove it, instead of a generic "duplicates detected" message.</li>
          <li>The update engine now runs under bash strict mode (set -uo pipefail) so unset variables and mid-pipeline failures surface immediately instead of silently.</li>
          <li>A failed repository refresh no longer marks a successful system upgrade as failed.</li>
          <li>The sudo keep-alive no longer leaves a short-lived background process behind when a run ends or is cancelled.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>Audit and independent-review fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Firmware updates no longer report success or force a reboot when the flash failed.</li>
          <li>Cancelling a run now stops it instead of continuing through the remaining steps.</li>
          <li>Reliable "already up to date" detection on non-English systems.</li>
          <li>Hardened the rollback and service-restart actions, and several packaging fixes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>First public release.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
